<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Advanced Scheduling and Prediction on Expert Analytics</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/projects/scheduling/</link><description>Recent content in Advanced Scheduling and Prediction on Expert Analytics</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://expertanalytics.no/projects/scheduling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pia Zacharias</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/pia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/pia/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pia is a physicist with more than ten years of experience in scientific
programming and data analysis. She holds a PhD in physics, which she obtained
from the University of Freiburg, Germany in 2010. She has been working as a
researcher, mentor and lecturer in astrophysics at different research
institutions across Europe before she joined Expert Analytics in 2018.
Her areas of expertise include numerical simulations of complex physical systems,
statistical data analysis and signal processing, as well machine learning applications
and visualization and handling of large datasets.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guttorm Kvaal</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/guttorm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/guttorm/</guid><description>&lt;p>Guttorm is a curious person with an interest and enthusiasm for
technology and problem solving. His academic background is focused
around applied mathematics, programming, and physics. He submitted his
master’s thesis the summer 2017 in the field of Computational Science
and Engineering at the University of Oslo / Simula.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>