<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Welcome on Expert Analytics</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/</link><description>Recent content in Welcome on Expert Analytics</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 20:22:13 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://expertanalytics.no/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Git</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/other/git/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:19:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/other/git/</guid><description>Version control systems are essential for any level of reliable code development. The by far most popular version control system is GIT, with its wide range of advanced tools.
Course Content In this course we will give an introduction to GIT and its functionality. We will go through interaction with repository, branching and merging, and how to address some corner case problems.
Prerequisite Some experience with an command-line interface tool.
Duration: 2 hours Tools Introduced GIT Git is a widely used source code management system for software development. It is a distributed revision control system with an emphasis on speed, data integrity, and support for distributed, non-linear workflows.</description></item><item><title>C/C++ and Python</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cross-language/c-python/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:19:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cross-language/c-python/</guid><description>Python, with its many advantages, is still by most standards considered a slow language. Any operation that is computationally intensive requires the program to be as fast as possible to keep the computational time to a minimum. To this extent, one can use a wrapper between Python and C/C++: The computational bottlenecks can be addressed in C/C++, while everything else can be done in Python.
Course Content In this course we will give an introduction to Swig in Python. We will go through how header files in C++ can be used to create a connection to create modules in Python. The course will also show how to integrate other languages as well.
Prerequisite This course requires some familiarity with the C++ programming language, introduced here.
This course requires some familiarity with the Python programming language, introduced here.
Duration: 1 hours Tools Introduced Swig Simplified Wrapper and Interface Generator (SWIG) is an open-source software tool used to connect computer programs or libraries written in C or C++ with scripting languages such as Python. SWIG will compile an interface file and generate code in regular C/C++ and the target programming language through shared libraries.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Python</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:16:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/introduction/</guid><description>An introduction to the Python programming language. An excellent starting point for those who have never used Python before, but want to learn what it is about.
Course Content The course will introduce how to create and use the following code structures:
Variables and data types for- and while-loops Branches Functions Classes The course also covers an introduction to the Python interpreter and code documentation for easy navigation in the Python landscape.
Prerequisite This course aims at the introduction to Python without any prior knowledge about the language.
Duration: 2-6 hours Tools introduced Python Python is a widely used high-level, general-purpose, interpreted, dynamic programming language. Its design philosophy emphasizes code readability, and its syntax allows programmers to express concepts in fewer lines of code than would be possible in languages such as C++ or Java. The language provides constructs intended to enable clear programs on both a small and large scale.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to C++</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cpp/introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 13:38:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cpp/introduction/</guid><description>An introduction to the C++ programming language. An excellent starting point for those who are familiar with programming, but who have never worked with C++.
Course Content The course will cover the following topics:
C++ specific syntax Data types and typecasting Overloading of functions and operators I/O in C++ Pointers Commonly used standard library classes Prerequisite Some experience with other programming languages.
Duration: 2-6 hours Tools Introduced C++ C++ is a widely used general-purpose, strongly typed, compiled programming language. C++ encompasses high-level features, such as objects and templates, as well as facilities for low-level memory manipulation. Due to its low-level features, C++ offers excellent performance, and is often used in performance-critical applications, such as drivers and embedded firmware. The high-level features of the language also makes it highly flexible, and its many uses include system software, client-server applications, and application software, such as video games.</description></item><item><title>Regular Expressions</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/other/regex/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:20:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/other/regex/</guid><description>Regular expressions are essentially a tiny, highly specialized programming language. It is a powerful tool for extracting meaningful information out of unstructured sources. A regular expression is mainly used in pattern matching with strings, or string matching, i.e. &amp;ldquo;find and replace&amp;rdquo;-like operations. Using this little language, you specify the rules for the set of possible strings that you want to match; this set might contain English sentences, or e-mail addresses, or TeX commands, or anything you like.
Course Content In this course the formal language of regular expression will be introduced. Afterwards we will show how the language can be applied to various test cases. We will also discuss the various regular expression dialects and how to implement regular expressions in a programming language like Python.
Prerequisite This course aims at the introduction to regular expression without any prior knowledge about the language.
Some experience with Python can be an advantage.
Duration: 2-6 hours Tools Introduced Python Regular Expression The Python regular expression module is an implementation of regular expression made available from inside of Python. The expression used here are the the Perl dialect, one of the most popular dialects of regular expression.</description></item><item><title>Fortran and Python</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cross-language/fortran-python/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:19:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cross-language/fortran-python/</guid><description>Fortran is a general-purpose, imperative programming language that is especially suited to numeric computation and scientific computing. It was once the dominating programming language in numerical intensive fields, such as physics, mechanics, chemistry and high-performance computing. To make use of the code developed in Fortran, it is prudent to integrate the code into other languages. One integration approach is to us f2py to integrate it into Python.
Course Content In this course we will give an introduction to f2py in Python. We will go through how header files in Fortran can be used create a connection to create modules in Python. The course will also show how to integrate other languages as well.
Prerequisite This course requires some familiarity with the Python programming language, introduced here.
Duration: 1 hours Tools Introduced F2Py f2py is an interface generator that provides a connection between Python and Fortran. It is a Python extension tool for creating Python C/API modules from signature files.</description></item><item><title>Numerical Python</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/numerical/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:17:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/numerical/</guid><description>The large majority of mathematical modeling requires proper numerical software. We at Expert Analytics believe that the corner stone for the vast majority of such problems should be solved using Python. (Though in many cases it should be combined with programs written in C++, as addressed here)
Course Content In this course we will give an introduction to numerical Python. We will focus on computational speed and illustrate how to process large data structures using Python&amp;rsquo;s minimal formulation. The course will also introduce some of the most popular numerical processing tools and visualize the results.
Prerequisite This course requires some familiarity with the Python programming language, introduced here.
Duration: 2-4 hours Tools introduced Numpy Numpy is the most popular tool for performing numerical operations in Python. The library consist of functions written in C, but with a Python explicit frontend. This gives Numpy computation speed comparable to buffered C, but the convenience of coding in Python. The Numpy syntax should be familiar to those experienced with Matlab. Scipy Scipy is a toolbox built on to Numpy and provide a vast collection of numerical optimization and processing tools. The toolbox contains modules for optimization, linear algebra, integration, interpolation, special functions, FFT, signal and image processing, ODE solvers and other tasks common in science and engineering. Matplotlib Matplotlib is the Scipy recommended library for plotting and visualization when using Numpy and Scipy. The library allows for easy production of publication quality figures in a variety of hardcopy formats and interactive environments across platforms.</description></item><item><title>Numerical C++</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cpp/numerical/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:06:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cpp/numerical/</guid><description>If a program is performing any form of numerical operations, it is likely that it will become the program bottleneck. To minimize the impact of the bottleneck, care must be taken to ensure that the code being executed is as optimized as possible.
Course Content In this course we will introduce the numerical library Armadillo. We will give an overview of the syntax, and how to employ the language to solve large-scale numerical problems.
Prerequisite This course requires some familiarity with the C++ programming language, introduced here.
Duration: 2 hours Tools Introduced Armadillo Armadillo is a linear algebra software library for the C++ programming language. It aims to provide efficient and streamlined base calculations, while at the same time having a straightforward and easy-to-use interface. Its intended target users are scientists and engineers.</description></item><item><title>Geographical Information Systems</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/gis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:17:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/gis/</guid><description>A geographic information system (GIS) is a system designed to capture, store, manipulate, analyze, manage, and present all types of spatial or geographical data. In other words, if a calculations involves using a map, you need to use GIS.
Course Content In this course, we will give an introduction to GIS. We will go through both how raster images and vector information can be imported, manipulated, brought together, visualized and exported.
Prerequisite The course requires familiarity with the Numpy, Scipy and Matplotlib libraries, introduced here.
Duration: 2 hours Tools Introduced Rasterio Rasterio employs GDAL under the hood for file I/O and raster formatting. Its functions typically accept and return Numpy ndarrays. Rasterio is designed to make working with geospatial raster data more productive. Fiona Fiona is OGR&amp;rsquo;s neat, nimble, no-nonsense API for Python programmers. Fiona is designed to be simple and dependable. It focuses on reading and writing data in standard Python IO style and relies upon familiar Python types and protocols such as files, dictionaries, mappings, and iterators instead of classes specific to OGR. Pyproj Pyproj allows for forward and inverse cartographic transformations and geodetic computations using the Proj.4 library, the current standard for such transformations and computations.</description></item><item><title>Templating and Metaprogramming</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cpp/templating/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:14:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cpp/templating/</guid><description>Templates are a powerful tool in C++ that allows you to write generalized functions and classes, enabling them to depend on free parameters that are set whenever they are used. This is commonly used to create functions that can take arguments of any type as input.
With the C++11 standard, variadic templates were introduced. Variadic templates not only allows you to make typesafe variadic functions, but also enables templates to be used for metaprogramming: writing code that writes code.
Course Content In this course, we will give an introduction to programming with C++ templates and variadic functions. Topics include:
Using templates to create type-independent functions and classes Creating variadic tempate functions - functions that take an arbitrary number of arguments, while being typesafe Metaprogramming with templates: make the compiler write some of your code Prerequisite This course requires familiarity with the C++ programming language.
Duration: 2-4 hours</description></item><item><title>Statistical Inference</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/statistics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:17:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/statistics/</guid><description>Datasets are in many applications getting so large and complex that traditional data processing applications are becoming inadequate. Challenges include analysis, capture, data curation, search, sharing, storage, transfer, visualization, querying and information privacy to mention some aspects of the problem.
Course Content In this course we will give an introduction to data frames; containers for large datasets. It give an overview of how to import and manipulate datasets, and perform various statistical estimations, with focus on how to interpret the datasets properly.
Prerequisite The course requires familiarity with the Numpy, Scipy and Matplotlib libraries, introduced here.
Duration: 2-6 hours Tools Introduced Pandas Pandas is a software library written for the Python for data manipulation and analysis. In particular, it offers data structures and operations for manipulating numerical tables and time series. Statsmodels Statsmodels is a Python module that allows users to explore data, estimate statistical models, and perform statistical tests. An extensive list of descriptive statistics, statistical tests, plotting functions, and result statistics are available for different types of data and each estimator.</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cpp/machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:15:05 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cpp/machine-learning/</guid><description>Machine learning is the field of study that gives computers the ability to learn without being explicitly programmed. It is the study and construction of algorithms that can learn from and make predictions on data. Such algorithms operate by building a model from example inputs in order to make data-driven predictions or decisions, rather than following strictly static program instructions. The term &amp;ldquo;machine learning&amp;rdquo; is an umbrella term and can be used to describe one of the following topics:
Classification: Identifying categories an object belongs to. Regression: Predict values associated with objects. Clustering: Automatically group similar objects into sets. Dimension reduction: Make large scale problems more manageable. Model selection: Find and calibrate the best models. Preprocessing: Normalizing of raw data preparing it for learning algorithms. Course Content In this course we will focus on the application of tools to perform various aspects of machine learning, using the Dlib library. We will touch base on how the various algorithms work.
Prerequisite The course requires familiarity with C++ programming language.
Duration: 4-6 hours Tools Introduced Dlib Dlib is a modern C++ toolkit containing machine learning algorithms and tools for creating complex software in C++. The software is open source and cross platform compatible, and also features more general purpose functionality e.g. linear algebra, image processing, GUI etc. The library supports a number of machine learning algorithms, such as Support Vector Machines and neural networks.</description></item><item><title>Testing Suites</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/testing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:17:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/testing/</guid><description>A development platform is only as good as the testing environment. As any project grows, a proper framework for implementing tests can provide an objective, independent view of the software to allow the business to appreciate and understand the risks of software implementation.
Course Content In this course, we will give an introduction to testing in Python. We will show how simple functionality can be integrated into the documentation through doctest, and how to scale the functionality.
Prerequisite This course requires some familiarity with the Python programming language, introduced here.
Duration: 1 Hour Tools Introduced Pytest Pytest is a testing framework aimed at making a minimal formulation, but yet scales well into complex functional testing for applications and libraries. It integrates well with most other testing frameworks available in Python, like Doctest, Nose and Unittest.</description></item><item><title>Deployment</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/deployment/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:17:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/deployment/</guid><description>Using libraries is an integral part of using Python properly. As a collection of tools grows, it will at some point make sense to make your own Python libraries.
Course Content In this course we will introduce code deployment in Python. In addition, some best practices advice will be discussed to let the code reflect the deployment.
Prerequisite This course requires some familiarity with the Python programming language, introduced here.
Duration: 1 hour Tools Introduced Distutils The Distutils package provides support for building and installing additional modules into a Python installation. The new modules may either be 100% pure Python, extension modules written in C, or collections of Python packages which include modules coded in both Python and C.</description></item><item><title>Web Development</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/web/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:18:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/web/</guid><description>Python is an excellent platform for creating web applications. One of the more popular tools for this task, that also embraces the expressiveness of Python, is the Flask framework.
Course Content Here you will learn how to get a basic website up and running using the Flask framework. We will also show how the application easily can be extended from the large collection of extensions, and how to maintain such an application. Some time will also be allotted to introducing Nginx.
Prerequisite This course requires some familiarity with the Python programming language, introduced here.
Experience with HTML/JS/CSS is recommended, but not required.
Duration: 2-8 hours Tools Introduced Flask Flask is a popular web framework written in Python. It is a minimal core that can be extended with features; using add-on modules for most features. Amongst the applications of Flask, we find both Pinterest and Linkedin. Nginx Nginx is a web server. It can act as a reverse proxy server for HTTP, HTTPS, SMTP, POP3, and IMAP protocols, as well as a load balancer and an HTTP cache.</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:18:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/machine-learning/</guid><description>Machine learning is the field of study that gives computers the ability to learn without being explicitly programmed. It is the study and construction of algorithms that can learn from and make predictions on data. Such algorithms operate by building a model from example inputs in order to make data-driven predictions or decisions, rather than following strictly static program instructions. The term &amp;ldquo;machine learning&amp;rdquo; is an umbrella term and can be used to describe one of the following topics:
Classification: Identifying categories an object belongs to. Regression: Predict values associated with objects. Clustering: Automatically group similar objects into sets. Dimension reduction: Make large-scale problems more manageable. Model selection: Find and calibrate the best models. Preprocessing: Normalizing of raw data preparing it for learning algorithms. Course Content In this course we will focus on the application of tools to perform various aspects of machine learning, using the Scikit-learn toolkit. We will touch base on how the various algorithms work.
Prerequisite The course requires familiarity with the Numpy, Scipy and Matplotlib libraries, introduced here.
Duration: 4-6 hours Tools Introduced Scikit-Learn Scikit-learn is an open source machine learning library for the Python programming language. It features various classification, regression and clustering algorithms, including support vector machines, random forests, gradient boosting, k-means and DBSCAN, and is designed to interoperate with the Python numerical and scientific libraries Numpy and Scipy.</description></item><item><title>Kate Heerema</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/kate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/kate/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kate holds a PhD in Marine Geology from Durham University, United Kingdom, and completed a post-doc at the University of Victoria, Canada. She is a problem solver, analytical thinker and loves a challenge. With her Earth Sciences background, she is an expert in big data analysis and visualisation, fieldwork planning and preparation, as well as instrument deployment. She has worked with a variety of geophysical data, and is always eager to dive into new data acquisition types. She has strong collaboration skills, extensive teaching experience and great communication skills.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Eric Matthews</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/eric/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/eric/</guid><description>&lt;p>Eric holds a Ph.D. in Nuclear Physics from Berkeley. His thesis was written on the nuclear data of fission yields. His main interests include nuclear medicine, data science and analysis, and statistics. Eric is currently working with Expert Analytics to develop its oncology research portfolio after the company joined the Oslo Cancer Cluster in November 2022. Eric retains an appointment on the research faculty at the Department of Nuclear Engineering at Berkeley.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Therese Renstrøm</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/therese/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/therese/</guid><description>&lt;p>Therese holds a Ph.D. in Experimental Nuclear Physics from the University of Oslo. Her thesis was awarded the YARA Birkeland Prize for outstanding contributions to
innovation and industry. Her main fields of expertise are developing real-time analytics tools and implementing machine learning and statistical models. The past years,
she has developed prototypes and set into production software tools for the petroleum-, processing- and medical industry.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>John M. Aiken</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/john/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/john/</guid><description>John is a computational scientist who has experience across disciplines in using machine learning, statistics, software development to reach solutions. John has worked on a variety of problems and enjoys learning new topics and new technology that connect across disciplines. At Expert Analytics John works on problems related to global scale spatio-temporal modeling and CO2 sequestration. John also is affiliated as Researcher at the University of Oslo in the Njord Centre for Studies of the Physics of the Earth.</description></item><item><title>Felix Kohler</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/felix/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/felix/</guid><description>&lt;p>Felix is a research scientist with experience in data analysis and scientific programming. He holds a PhD in physics and worked in various interdisciplinary projects both as a Postdoc and Researcher in an academic setting as well as a senior researcher in industry. Felix has a background in both experimental studies as well as mathematical and numerical modelling. His creativity, analytical mindset and scientific experience provide him with a solid foundation for finding solutions to complex problems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alessandro Marin</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/alessandro/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/alessandro/</guid><description>Alessandro has a PhD in Physics and 10+ years of corporate and academic experience in software development, machine learning, scientific research, and technical troubleshooting. Alessandro is eager to work with new technologies and is experienced in solving problems analytically and with creativity. At the same time he is proficient in handling technical issues and in communicating with end users.</description></item><item><title>Kine Onsum Moseid</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/kine/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/kine/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kine is an organized scientific programmer that likes to solve problems from a big picture approach. She submitted her PhD thesis in Climate Science in December of 2021, and during her doctorate she analyzed radiation and air pollution data from a multitude of climate model simulations and compared them with observations. This work gave insight in big data analytics and visualisation, especially regarding time series and how to avoid common pitfalls like comparing apples and oranges. She enjoys working with large datasets, learning new things, and communicating/teaching science.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Solveig Næss</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/solveig/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/solveig/</guid><description>Solveig is an enthusiastic problem solver with strong collaboration skills. With a PhD in brain physics, she enjoys applying mathematics, physics and programming to develop new methods and answer complex questions.</description></item><item><title>Kristine Sønstevold Beckmann</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/kristine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/kristine/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kristine has a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree and three years experience as a PhD-student in Nuclear Physics. She has accumulated extensive practice with statistical analysis of sensor data and problem solving using programming tools such as Python and C++. Kristine has performed analyses consisting of handling raw data, performing calibrations, doing time series analysis, statistical fitting of peak distributions and doing model simulations in order to compare to experimental data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Marco Nava</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/marco/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/marco/</guid><description>&lt;p>Marco holds a Ph.D in computational Condensed Matter Physics, with
a strong focus on quantum and classical atomistic simulation methods.
Throughout his decade-long career he has worked on both software development -
mainly in C++ and Python - and research intensive projects across several
research fields ranging from low-temperature physics to computational chemistry
and biophysics. This experience, along with his robust mathematical and
coding background, allows him to be a broad and thorough problem solver, well
capable of working both independently and as a team member.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Naeeme Danesh Moghaddam</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/naeeme/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/naeeme/</guid><description>&lt;p>Naeeme is an enthusiastic software developer with many years of experience as a
project engineer. Before joining our team, she worked in the field of 3D
modelling and CFD simulation of reactive and non-reactive flows, employing
high-performance computing and immersive virtual reality environments to
optimize the performance of industrial units. This allowed her to gain
experience in solving complex problems using her expertise in software
development combined with her knowledge in fluid dynamics, chemical
thermodynamics, mass and heat transfer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mats Brun</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/mats/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/mats/</guid><description>Mats has a PhD (2019) in applied and computational mathematics (University of Bergen, Bergen, Norway), in addition to a postdoctoral experience in biomathematics at the University of Oslo, Oslo, Norway (2020-2021). He has experience and interest in biomathematics, fluid mechanics, flow in porous media, heat transfer, solid mechanics, coupled systems, among others. Moreover, he has programming experience in Python, Java, Matlab and Haskell. Mats is an analytical and creative problem solver, whose expertise relies on diverse experience with mathematical modeling and numerical programming, with applications ranging from geothermal energy storage to evolutionary biology, in addition to several teaching experiences.</description></item><item><title>Pushing AI to the EDGE!</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/posts/dais/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 12:56:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/posts/dais/</guid><description>&lt;p>Starting in May 2021, Expert Analytics is participating in the European Horizon2020 project
&lt;a href="https://dais-project.eu/">Distributed Artificial Intelligent Systems - DAIS&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Together with our Norwegian partners Step Solutions and Jotne EPM, Expert Analytics is developing
methods for distributed artificial intelligence applied to high frequency data. This enables us to
monitor the health status of industry assets without having to send large amounts of data to the
cloud for analysis. This is particularly beneficiary for assets in remote locations with limited
access to bandwidth, like hydropower, shipping and offshore industry.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sebastian Franco Ulloa</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/sebas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/sebas/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sebastian is a curious person always looking to learn about
new topics and combining them into novel solutions to complex
problems. He received his PhD in biocomputional sciences in
March 2021 from the Italian Institute of Technology/University
of Bologna, where he studied how nanomaterials interact with
physiological environments. He is experienced in molecular
simulations, data visualization, and scientific writing.
In more recent years, Sebastian has been applying bioinformatic
methods to genomics, proteomics, and transcriptomics data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thomas Zengaffinen-Morris</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/tzm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/tzm/</guid><description>Thomas has a background in Earth Sciences and likes solving challenging problems. During his education at NGI Oslo, UiO, and ETH Zurich, he gained valuable scripting skills to automate processes, analyse and visualise data, and perform numerical simulations.</description></item><item><title>Expert Analytics and scientific outreach</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/posts/ada_estbook/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 20:09:04 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/posts/ada_estbook/</guid><description>&lt;p>A new book showcasing the scientific challenges to be tackled by the European Solar Telescope (EST) has just seen the light. EST is a 4-meter aperture telescope designed to investigate the Sun with unprecedented detail. Equipped with state-of-the-art instruments, it will help scientists understand the magnetic coupling of the solar atmosphere. EST will be the largest solar telescope ever built in Europe and it&amp;rsquo;s expected to see the so-called first light in 2027. EST is a pan-European project involving 18 countries and financed by EU&amp;rsquo;s Horizon 2020 Research and Innovation programme.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A series of short articles on the science problems to be addressed by EST were published on social
media between May 2018 and April 2020. The goal was to raise awareness of solar physics and the importance
of the future EST among a general, non-specialised audience. A total of 77 articles were written by professional
solar astronomers from 30 different European research centers and universities. All the articles are now collected in this book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Max Endo Kokubun</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/max/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/max/</guid><description>&lt;p>Max has a PhD (2014) in Aerospace Engineering (INPE, Brazil) and two postdoctoral experiences: one in Applied Mathematics, at IMPA (Brazil, 2014-2016) and another in Chemistry, at the University of Bergen (2016-2019). He has experience and interest in multiphase flow, reactive flows, flows in porous media, heat transfer, CFD, to name a few. Additionally, he has programming experience in Fortran, Matlab, Python and Octave.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More than the scientific capabilities, Max&amp;rsquo;s expertise relies on its experience in bridging fundamental and applied science.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fredrik Meyer</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/fredrik/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/fredrik/</guid><description>Fredrik holds a PhD in algebraic geometry, and enjoys programming and teaching. He enjoys explaining hard concepts, both in a one-to-many and one-to-one setting. He enjoys encountering new problems, and spending time thinking on creative solutions. As a software consultant he has learned how to build robust software and write clean and maintainable code.
Before joining us, Fredrik worked at Bekk Consulting, where he has worked with both frontend and backend systems.</description></item><item><title>Sigmund Slang</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/sigmund/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/sigmund/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sigmund submitted his masters&amp;rsquo;s degree in Geophysics and Seismology at
the University of Oslo in 2019. The subject of the thesis was Attenuation
of Seismic Interference Noise using Convolutional Neural Networks and was
written in collaboration with CGG Services AS. This work gave insight in
the fields of machine learning and seismic signal processing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Expert Analytics in the press: article about the Sun published in Spanish newspaper</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/posts/ada_newspaper_article/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/posts/ada_newspaper_article/</guid><description>&lt;p>What will happen to the Sun when it dies?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The article entitled “What will happen to the Sun when it dies?” was published in the Spanish newspaper El Pais on October 2, 2019. El Pais is the main general newspaper in Spain. The article (in Spanish) can be found &lt;a href="https://elpais.com/elpais/2019/09/30/ciencia/1569831387_907062.html">here&lt;/a>. Ada is a data scientist at Expert Analytics with a background in academia. Her field of research is Solar Physics, and in addition to doing research she communicates science within education &amp;amp; outreach activities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Robert Solli</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/robert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/robert/</guid><description>&lt;p>Robert Solli is a specialist in scientific programming, with expertise in
mathematical optimisation, statistical analysis and machine learning. He has
solved a varied set of problems with this skillset, from understanding complex
physical systems to increasing student volunteer participation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Robert Hagala</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/rh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/rh/</guid><description>&lt;p>Robert has a PhD in astrophysics, with a specialisation in
cosmological simulations. He is experienced with numerical
modelling of physical systems, statistical analysis of large data sets,
high-performance computing, and cloud based applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ada Ortiz-Carbonell</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ada/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ada/</guid><description>Ada is a senior researcher with 20 years of academic experience in the field of Astrophysics during which she taught, mentored students, organized several international conferences and led her own research projects. She is engaged in scientific communication and outreach, having published two books, delivered public lectures, appeared in the media explaining solar physics to a general audience and been nominated as TED speaker. She decided to take on a new challenge and apply her skills in the industry. Ada enjoys analyzing complex problems as well as extracting valuable information out of data.</description></item><item><title>Ata Karakci</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ata/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ata/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ata holds a PhD in physics with specialisation in astrophysics which he obtained from Brown University in 2014. Before joining the Expert Analytics team, he has worked as a postdoctoral researcher at the University of Oslo and Universite Paris VII. His expertise includes statistical analysis of large data sets, numerical modelling, signal processing, imaging, and programming.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interview with Simen on his PhD</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/posts/simen_phd_interview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/posts/simen_phd_interview/</guid><description>&lt;p>Simen Tennøe recently defended his PhD thesis in computational neuroscience.
In this context, the University of Oslo interviewed him along with two of his
co-PhD students on the cross-disciplinary work they have performed during their PhDs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can read the article &lt;a href="https://titan.uio.no/node/3368">here&lt;/a> (in Norwegian).
For the especially interested, a longer summary of his PhD can be found
&lt;a href="https://www.mn.uio.no/ifi/forskning/aktuelt/arrangementer/disputaser/2019/pressemelding_tennoe.pdf">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thomas Golding</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/thomas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/thomas/</guid><description>&lt;p>Thomas is interested in bringing to life the potential of data for automation
and insight purposes. He will happily engage in the various steps of the
process, from analysis and machine learning to data collection and software
development.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gry M. Tveten</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/gry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/gry/</guid><description>&lt;p>Gry is a curious, efficient and pragmatic problem solver. She completed her PhD in experimental nuclear physics at the University of Oslo in 2013 and most of her PhD work was carried out at CERN. She has 6 years of post doc experience. Her recent work focused on understanding how the elements are created in stellar processes. This research required developing detection systems, analyzing data, visualization and carrying out complex simulations. She has also teaching experience, including course development at university level and has led her own projects since she completed her PhD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diako Darian</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/diako/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/diako/</guid><description>&lt;p>Diako holds a Ph.D. in Computational Mathematics from the University of Oslo. As
a student at both Mathematics and Physics departments at the University of Oslo,
he has acquired a broad knowledge in various physical and mathematical theories,
and numerical methods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Simen Tennøe</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/simen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/simen/</guid><description>&lt;p>Simen is a computational scientist who finished his Ph.D. in computational
neuroscience in 2019. He has a background from computational astrophysics
where he wrote software for finding clusters of galaxies in cosmological N-body
simulations. His Ph.D. focused on quantifying uncertainties in computational
models of neurons and neural networks and he created a Python toolbox for
performing these calculations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kent-Andre Mardal</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/kent/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/kent/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kent-Andre is a Professor of Applied Mathematics at the University of Oslo. He
has extensive experience with computational modeling, multi-physics
simulations, high-performance computing, and scientific software development
(Python and C++).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trygve Bærland</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/trygve/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/trygve/</guid><description>&lt;p>Trygve holds a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Industrial Mathematics at NTNU from 2015, and
a Ph.D. in Computational Mathematics at the University of Oslo from
2019. In his thesis Trygve developed, analysed and implemented efficient
algorithms for solving systems of equations related to fluid flow in the brain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alocias Mariadason</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/alocias/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/alocias/</guid><description>&lt;p>Alocias has a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in physics from the University of Oslo, submitted
in spring 2018. The subject of the thesis was Quantum Monte Carlo Simulations
of Quantum dots constrained in single- and double well potentials. He solved
the numerical problem for both systems with new analytic expressions which had
not been explicitly done before and a newer method with roots in machine
learning to further improve upon the results.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interview with Jonathan</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/posts/interview-with-jonathan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/posts/interview-with-jonathan/</guid><description>&lt;p>The University of Oslo recently interviewed Jonathan to learn how he
applies the knowledge acquired during his studies in his current job
as a senior consultant and problem solver in Expert Analytics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read the article
&lt;a href="https://www.uio.no/studier/program/matematikk-informatikk/karriereintervjuer/jonathan-feinberg.html">here&lt;/a>
(written in Norwegian).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pia Zacharias</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/pia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/pia/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pia is a physicist with more than ten years of experience in scientific
programming and data analysis. She holds a PhD in physics, which she obtained
from the University of Freiburg, Germany in 2010. She has been working as a
researcher, mentor and lecturer in astrophysics at different research
institutions across Europe before she joined Expert Analytics in 2018.
Her areas of expertise include numerical simulations of complex physical systems,
statistical data analysis and signal processing, as well machine learning applications
and visualization and handling of large datasets.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Roar Emaus</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/roar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/roar/</guid><description>&lt;p>Roar has a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in High Energy Physics from the University of Oslo,
completed in 2018. In his thesis he studied two different models of particle
production at high energies, one statistical using the thermodynamical
equations and one using the properties of a theoretical particle called
Pomeron.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Johannes talking at the Rust Meetup in Oslo</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/posts/johannes-rust-meetup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 12:08:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/posts/johannes-rust-meetup/</guid><description>&lt;p>The topic of the session was &amp;ldquo;Barriers to Rust adoption in Norway&amp;rdquo;. A
lot of developers, it seems, are using Rust at their spare time for
pet projects, but few professionally. Some barriers were identified,
like the size of the community making it hard for businesses to commit
to developing production software in Rust. The community agreed to
take action and provide training at both beginner and intermediate
level to spread the language, which we think is an excellent and
active approach to overcome this issue.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sebastian Gjertsen</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/sebastian/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/sebastian/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sebastian holds a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in applied mathematics from the
University of Oslo and Simula Research Laboratory, finished
in 2017. In his thesis he built a Fluid-Structure Interaction solver
with Python using the FEniCS platform. This also included working with
supercomputers parallelizing the computational efforts. During his
studies he gained knowledge in algorithms, numerical computing and
programming in different languages.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alexander Fleischer</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/alexander/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/alexander/</guid><description>&lt;p>Alexander is a seasoned programmer specializing in Python;
a result of more than three years of professional experience as a Python
systems developer and over a decade programming in Python.
He has worked in both the public transport sector and the energy sector
on several projects combining back-end and front-end development.
Alexander holds a master&amp;rsquo;s thesis in computational quantum physics from
the University of Oslo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Andreas Slyngstad</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/andreas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/andreas/</guid><description>&lt;p>Andreas submitted his master’s thesis in applied mathematics from the
University of Oslo and Simula Research Laboratory. In his thesis he
investigated numerical schemes, for solving equations describing
Fluid-Structure Interaction, using Python and FEniCS. His academic background
has given him several tools and approaches for solving complex problems in a
computational/software domain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guttorm Kvaal</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/guttorm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/guttorm/</guid><description>&lt;p>Guttorm is a curious person with an interest and enthusiasm for
technology and problem solving. His academic background is focused
around applied mathematics, programming, and physics. He submitted his
master’s thesis the summer 2017 in the field of Computational Science
and Engineering at the University of Oslo / Simula.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jakob Schreiner</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/jakob/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/jakob/</guid><description>&lt;p>Jakob submitted his master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computational Science and Engineering at
the University of Oslo in 2016. His educational background is in mathematics
and computational science applied on mechanical problems using numerical
methods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Eivind Storm Aarnæs</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/eivind/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/eivind/</guid><description>&lt;p>Eivind has a masters degree in Computational Science from the
University of Oslo, completed in 2016. His project investigated a
particle system modeling linear elasticity, and accelerating linear
algebra computations using GPUs. From the studies leading to his
degree he has gained broad knowledge about algorithms, numerical
mathematics, and programming in several languages.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vinzenz Gregor Eck</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/vinzenz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/vinzenz/</guid><description>&lt;p>Vinzenz is a curious, pragmatic, creative problem solver. He holds a
PhD in biomechanical engineering, focusing on stochastic simulations
of the blood flow in the human arterial system. This interdisciplinary
work included working within engineering, medicine, biology, software
development and statistics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ola Skavhaug</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ola/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ola/</guid><description>Founder and CSO of Expert Analytics. Loves mixing high and low level languages
to join flexibility and high perfomance computing.</description></item><item><title>Åsmund Ødegård</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/asmund/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/asmund/</guid><description>Founder and CEO of Expert Analytics. Enjoys developing small and large
systems in a number of languages and environments. Makes sure that
everyting is working well, both with clients and internally.</description></item></channel></rss>