<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on Expert Analytics</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on Expert Analytics</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:18:30 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to Python</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:16:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p>An introduction to the Python programming language. An excellent
starting point for those who have never used Python before, but want
to learn what it is about.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="course-content">Course Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The course will introduce how to create and use the following code
structures:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Variables and data types&lt;/li>
&lt;li>for- and while-loops&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Branches&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Functions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Classes&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The course also covers an introduction to the Python interpreter and
code documentation for easy navigation in the Python landscape.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisite">Prerequisite&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This course aims at the introduction to Python without any prior
knowledge about the language.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="duration-2-6-hours">Duration: 2-6 hours&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="tools-introduced">Tools introduced&lt;/h2>
&lt;dl>
&lt;dt>Python&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Python is a widely used high-level, general-purpose, interpreted,
dynamic programming language. Its design philosophy emphasizes code
readability, and its syntax allows programmers to express concepts
in fewer lines of code than would be possible in languages such as
C++ or Java. The language provides constructs intended to enable
clear programs on both a small and large scale.&lt;/dd>
&lt;/dl></description></item><item><title>Numerical Python</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/numerical/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:17:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/numerical/</guid><description>&lt;p>The large majority of mathematical modeling requires proper numerical
software. We at Expert Analytics believe that the corner stone for the
vast majority of such problems should be solved using Python. (Though
in many cases it should be combined with programs written in C++, as
addressed &lt;a href="https://expertanalytics.no/training/cross-language/c-python/">here&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="course-content">Course Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this course we will give an introduction to numerical Python. We
will focus on computational speed and illustrate how to process large
data structures using Python&amp;rsquo;s minimal formulation. The course will
also introduce some of the most popular numerical processing tools and
visualize the results.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisite">Prerequisite&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This course requires some familiarity with the Python programming
language, introduced here.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="duration-2-4-hours">Duration: 2-4 hours&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="tools-introduced">Tools introduced&lt;/h2>
&lt;dl>
&lt;dt>Numpy&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Numpy is the most popular tool for performing numerical operations
in Python. The library consist of functions written in C, but with a
Python explicit frontend. This gives Numpy computation speed
comparable to buffered C, but the convenience of coding in
Python. The Numpy syntax should be familiar to those experienced
with Matlab.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>Scipy&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Scipy is a toolbox built on to Numpy and provide a vast collection
of numerical optimization and processing tools. The toolbox contains
modules for optimization, linear algebra, integration,
interpolation, special functions, FFT, signal and image processing,
ODE solvers and other tasks common in science and engineering.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>Matplotlib&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Matplotlib is the Scipy recommended library for plotting and
visualization when using Numpy and Scipy. The library allows for
easy production of publication quality figures in a variety of
hardcopy formats and interactive environments across platforms.&lt;/dd>
&lt;/dl></description></item><item><title>Geographical Information Systems</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/gis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:17:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/gis/</guid><description>&lt;p>A geographic information system (GIS) is a system designed to capture,
store, manipulate, analyze, manage, and present all types of spatial
or geographical data. In other words, if a calculations involves using
a map, you need to use GIS.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="course-content">Course Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this course, we will give an introduction to GIS. We will go
through both how raster images and vector information can be imported,
manipulated, brought together, visualized and exported.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisite">Prerequisite&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The course requires familiarity with the
&lt;a href="https://www.numpy.org/">Numpy&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://scipy.org/">Scipy&lt;/a> and
&lt;a href="https://matplotlib.org/">Matplotlib&lt;/a> libraries, introduced
&lt;a href="https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/numerical/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="duration-2-hours">Duration: 2 hours&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="tools-introduced">Tools Introduced&lt;/h2>
&lt;dl>
&lt;dt>Rasterio&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>&lt;a href="https://github.com/mapbox/rasterio">Rasterio&lt;/a> employs
&lt;a href="https://gdal.org/">GDAL&lt;/a> under the hood for file I/O and raster
formatting. Its functions typically accept and return Numpy
ndarrays. Rasterio is designed to make working with geospatial
raster data more productive.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>Fiona&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>&lt;a href="https://github.com/Toblerity/Fiona">Fiona&lt;/a> is
&lt;a href="https://gdal.org/">OGR&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;s neat, nimble, no-nonsense API for Python
programmers. Fiona is designed to be simple and dependable. It
focuses on reading and writing data in standard Python IO style and
relies upon familiar Python types and protocols such as files,
dictionaries, mappings, and iterators instead of classes specific to
OGR.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>Pyproj&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>&lt;a href="https://github.com/jswhit/pyproj">Pyproj&lt;/a> allows for forward and
inverse cartographic transformations and geodetic computations using
the &lt;a href="https://github.com/OSGeo/proj.4">Proj.4&lt;/a> library, the current
standard for such transformations and computations.&lt;/dd>
&lt;/dl></description></item><item><title>Statistical Inference</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/statistics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:17:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/statistics/</guid><description>&lt;p>Datasets are in many applications getting so large and complex that
traditional data processing applications are becoming
inadequate. Challenges include analysis, capture, data curation,
search, sharing, storage, transfer, visualization, querying and
information privacy to mention some aspects of the problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="course-content">Course Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this course we will give an introduction to data frames; containers
for large datasets. It give an overview of how to import and
manipulate datasets, and perform various statistical estimations, with
focus on how to interpret the datasets properly.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisite">Prerequisite&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The course requires familiarity with the
&lt;a href="https://www.numpy.org/">Numpy&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://scipy.org/">Scipy&lt;/a> and
&lt;a href="https://matplotlib.org/">Matplotlib&lt;/a> libraries, introduced
&lt;a href="https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/numerical/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="duration-2-6-hours">Duration: 2-6 hours&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="tools-introduced">Tools Introduced&lt;/h2>
&lt;dl>
&lt;dt>Pandas&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>&lt;a href="https://pandas.pydata.org/">Pandas&lt;/a> is a software library written
for the Python for data manipulation and analysis. In particular, it
offers data structures and operations for manipulating numerical
tables and time series.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>Statsmodels&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>&lt;a href="https://www.statsmodels.org/stable/index.html">Statsmodels&lt;/a> is a
Python module that allows users to explore data, estimate
statistical models, and perform statistical tests. An extensive list
of descriptive statistics, statistical tests, plotting functions,
and result statistics are available for different types of data and
each estimator.&lt;/dd>
&lt;/dl></description></item><item><title>Testing Suites</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/testing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:17:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/testing/</guid><description>&lt;p>A development platform is only as good as the testing environment. As
any project grows, a proper framework for implementing tests can
provide an objective, independent view of the software to allow the
business to appreciate and understand the risks of software
implementation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="course-content">Course Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this course, we will give an introduction to testing in Python. We
will show how simple functionality can be integrated into the
documentation through doctest, and how to scale the functionality.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisite">Prerequisite&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This course requires some familiarity with the Python programming
language, introduced &lt;a href="https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/introduction/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="duration-1-hour">Duration: 1 Hour&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="tools-introduced">Tools Introduced&lt;/h2>
&lt;dl>
&lt;dt>Pytest&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>&lt;a href="https://www.pytest.org/">Pytest&lt;/a> is a testing framework aimed at
making a minimal formulation, but yet scales well into complex
functional testing for applications and libraries. It integrates
well with most other testing frameworks available in Python, like
&lt;a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/doctest.html">Doctest&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://nose.readthedocs.io">Nose&lt;/a> and
&lt;a href="https://docs.python.org/3/library/unittest.html">Unittest&lt;/a>.&lt;/dd>
&lt;/dl></description></item><item><title>Deployment</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/deployment/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:17:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/deployment/</guid><description>&lt;p>Using libraries is an integral part of using Python properly. As a
collection of tools grows, it will at some point make sense to make
your own Python libraries.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="course-content">Course Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this course we will introduce code deployment in Python. In
addition, some best practices advice will be discussed to let the code
reflect the deployment.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisite">Prerequisite&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This course requires some familiarity with the Python programming
language, introduced &lt;a href="https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/introduction/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="duration-1-hour">Duration: 1 hour&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="tools-introduced">Tools Introduced&lt;/h2>
&lt;dl>
&lt;dt>Distutils&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>The Distutils package provides support for building and installing
additional modules into a Python installation. The new modules may
either be 100% pure Python, extension modules written in C, or
collections of Python packages which include modules coded in both
Python and C.&lt;/dd>
&lt;/dl></description></item><item><title>Web Development</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/web/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:18:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/web/</guid><description>&lt;p>Python is an excellent platform for creating web applications. One of
the more popular tools for this task, that also embraces the
expressiveness of Python, is the &lt;a href="http://flask.pocoo.org/">Flask&lt;/a>
framework.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="course-content">Course Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Here you will learn how to get a basic website up and running using
the Flask framework. We will also show how the application easily can
be extended from the large collection of extensions, and how to
maintain such an application. Some time will also be allotted to
introducing &lt;a href="https://nginx.org/">Nginx&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisite">Prerequisite&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This course requires some familiarity with the Python programming
language, introduced &lt;a href="https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/introduction/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Experience with HTML/JS/CSS is recommended, but not required.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="duration-2-8-hours">Duration: 2-8 hours&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="tools-introduced">Tools Introduced&lt;/h2>
&lt;dl>
&lt;dt>Flask&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Flask is a popular web framework written in Python. It is a minimal
core that can be extended with features; using add-on modules for
most features. Amongst the applications of Flask, we find both
Pinterest and Linkedin.&lt;/dd>
&lt;dt>Nginx&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>Nginx is a web server. It can act as a reverse proxy server for
HTTP, HTTPS, SMTP, POP3, and IMAP protocols, as well as a load
balancer and an HTTP cache.&lt;/dd>
&lt;/dl></description></item><item><title>Machine Learning</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:18:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/machine-learning/</guid><description>&lt;p>Machine learning is the field of study that gives computers the
ability to learn without being explicitly programmed. It is the study
and construction of algorithms that can learn from and make
predictions on data. Such algorithms operate by building a model from
example inputs in order to make data-driven predictions or decisions,
rather than following strictly static program instructions. The term
&amp;ldquo;machine learning&amp;rdquo; is an umbrella term and can be used to describe one
of the following topics:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Classification:&lt;/strong> Identifying categories an object belongs to.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Regression:&lt;/strong> Predict values associated with objects.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Clustering:&lt;/strong> Automatically group similar objects into sets.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Dimension reduction:&lt;/strong> Make large-scale problems more manageable.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Model selection:&lt;/strong> Find and calibrate the best models.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Preprocessing:&lt;/strong> Normalizing of raw data preparing it for learning
algorithms.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="course-content">Course Content&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this course we will focus on the application of tools to perform
various aspects of machine learning, using the
&lt;a href="https://scikit-learn.org/">Scikit-learn&lt;/a> toolkit. We will touch base
on how the various algorithms work.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisite">Prerequisite&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The course requires familiarity with the
&lt;a href="https://www.numpy.org/">Numpy&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://scipy.org/">Scipy&lt;/a> and
&lt;a href="https://matplotlib.org/">Matplotlib&lt;/a> libraries, introduced
&lt;a href="https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/numerical/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="duration-4-6-hours">Duration: 4-6 hours&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="tools-introduced">Tools Introduced&lt;/h2>
&lt;dl>
&lt;dt>Scikit-Learn&lt;/dt>
&lt;dd>&lt;a href="https://scikit-learn.org/">Scikit-learn&lt;/a> is an open source machine
learning library for the Python programming language. It features
various classification, regression and clustering algorithms,
including support vector machines, random forests, gradient
boosting, k-means and DBSCAN, and is designed to interoperate with
the Python numerical and scientific libraries Numpy and Scipy.&lt;/dd>
&lt;/dl></description></item></channel></rss>