<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on Expert Analytics</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on Expert Analytics</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:05:01 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to Python</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:16:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/introduction/</guid><description>An introduction to the Python programming language. An excellent starting point for those who have never used Python before, but want to learn what it is about.
Course Content The course will introduce how to create and use the following code structures:
Variables and data types for- and while-loops Branches Functions Classes The course also covers an introduction to the Python interpreter and code documentation for easy navigation in the Python landscape.</description></item><item><title>Numerical Python</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/numerical/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:17:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/numerical/</guid><description>The large majority of mathematical modeling requires proper numerical software. We at Expert Analytics believe that the corner stone for the vast majority of such problems should be solved using Python. (Though in many cases it should be combined with programs written in C++, as addressed here)
Course Content In this course we will give an introduction to numerical Python. We will focus on computational speed and illustrate how to process large data structures using Python&amp;rsquo;s minimal formulation.</description></item><item><title>Geographical Information Systems</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/gis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:17:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/gis/</guid><description>A geographic information system (GIS) is a system designed to capture, store, manipulate, analyze, manage, and present all types of spatial or geographical data. In other words, if a calculations involves using a map, you need to use GIS.
Course Content In this course, we will give an introduction to GIS. We will go through both how raster images and vector information can be imported, manipulated, brought together, visualized and exported.</description></item><item><title>Statistical Inference</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/statistics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:17:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/statistics/</guid><description>Datasets are in many applications getting so large and complex that traditional data processing applications are becoming inadequate. Challenges include analysis, capture, data curation, search, sharing, storage, transfer, visualization, querying and information privacy to mention some aspects of the problem.
Course Content In this course we will give an introduction to data frames; containers for large datasets. It give an overview of how to import and manipulate datasets, and perform various statistical estimations, with focus on how to interpret the datasets properly.</description></item><item><title>Testing Suites</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/testing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:17:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/testing/</guid><description>A development platform is only as good as the testing environment. As any project grows, a proper framework for implementing tests can provide an objective, independent view of the software to allow the business to appreciate and understand the risks of software implementation.
Course Content In this course, we will give an introduction to testing in Python. We will show how simple functionality can be integrated into the documentation through doctest, and how to scale the functionality.</description></item><item><title>Deployment</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/deployment/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:17:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/deployment/</guid><description>Using libraries is an integral part of using Python properly. As a collection of tools grows, it will at some point make sense to make your own Python libraries.
Course Content In this course we will introduce code deployment in Python. In addition, some best practices advice will be discussed to let the code reflect the deployment.
Prerequisite This course requires some familiarity with the Python programming language, introduced here.</description></item><item><title>Web Development</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/web/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:18:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/web/</guid><description>Python is an excellent platform for creating web applications. One of the more popular tools for this task, that also embraces the expressiveness of Python, is the Flask framework.
Course Content Here you will learn how to get a basic website up and running using the Flask framework. We will also show how the application easily can be extended from the large collection of extensions, and how to maintain such an application.</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:18:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/python/machine-learning/</guid><description>Machine learning is the field of study that gives computers the ability to learn without being explicitly programmed. It is the study and construction of algorithms that can learn from and make predictions on data. Such algorithms operate by building a model from example inputs in order to make data-driven predictions or decisions, rather than following strictly static program instructions. The term &amp;ldquo;machine learning&amp;rdquo; is an umbrella term and can be used to describe one of the following topics:</description></item></channel></rss>