<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Systems Development on Expert Analytics</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/services/systems/</link><description>Recent content in Systems Development on Expert Analytics</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://expertanalytics.no/services/systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Daniel Marelius Bjørnstad</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/daniel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/daniel/</guid><description>&lt;p>Daniel is a seasoned software developer with a PhD in neuroscience, specializing in data analysis and cloud software
development. With expertise in multiple stages of project development, Daniel’s work spans from the initial definition
of project goals and value propositions to the deployment of final products, including services, dashboards, reports,
production models, and APIs. His background in neuroscience provides a strong foundation in complex data processing and
analysis, allowing him to tackle challenging problems in diverse domains. He started working professionally with software development in 2016.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alexander Fleischer</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/alexander/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/alexander/</guid><description>&lt;p>Alexander is a senior software developer specializing in backend and system
development in Python.
His experience with Python dates back to 2010, and he has been working
professionally with system development in Python since 2018.
During his career, he has worked in several platform and product teams
in both the public transport sector and the energy sector.
Alexander holds a master&amp;rsquo;s thesis in computational quantum physics from
the University of Oslo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guttorm Kvaal</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/guttorm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/guttorm/</guid><description>&lt;p>Guttorm is a curious person with an interest and enthusiasm for
technology and problem solving. His academic background is focused
around applied mathematics, programming, and physics. He submitted his
master’s thesis the summer 2017 in the field of Computational Science
and Engineering at the University of Oslo / Simula.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>