<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Systems Development on Expert Analytics</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/services/systems/</link><description>Recent content in Systems Development on Expert Analytics</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://expertanalytics.no/services/systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fredrik Meyer</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/fredrik/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/fredrik/</guid><description>Fredrik holds a PhD in algebraic geometry, and enjoys programming and teaching. He enjoys explaining hard concepts, both in a one-to-many and one-to-one setting. He enjoys encountering new problems, and spending time thinking on creative solutions. As a software consultant he has learned how to build robust software and write clean and maintainable code.
Before joining us, Fredrik worked at Bekk Consulting, where he has worked with both frontend and backend systems.</description></item><item><title>Emil Løvgren</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/emil/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/emil/</guid><description>&lt;p>Analyst, strategist and technology enthusiast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Broad industry insight and project management experience from cross-industry collaboration projects, business development, research strategy, and project planning and execution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trygve Bærland</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/trygve/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/trygve/</guid><description>&lt;p>Trygve holds a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Industrial Mathematics at NTNU from 2015, and
a Ph.D. in Computational Mathematics at the University of Oslo from
2019. In his thesis Trygve developed, analysed and implemented efficient
algorithms for solving systems of equations related to fluid flow in the brain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alexander Fleischer</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/alexander/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/alexander/</guid><description>&lt;p>Alexander is a seasoned programmer specializing in Python;
a result of more than three years of professional experience as a Python
systems developer and over a decade programming in Python.
He has worked in both the public transport sector and the energy sector
on several projects combining back-end and front-end development.
Alexander holds a master&amp;rsquo;s thesis in computational quantum physics from
the University of Oslo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guttorm Kvaal</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/guttorm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/guttorm/</guid><description>&lt;p>Guttorm is a curious person with an interest and enthusiasm for
technology and problem solving. His academic background is focused
around applied mathematics, programming, and physics. He submitted his
master’s thesis the summer 2017 in the field of Computational Science
and Engineering at the University of Oslo / Simula.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Martin Alnæs</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/martin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/martin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Martin is an expert scientific programmer with a PhD in computational
science and more than a decade of software engineering experience from
research and industry. This combination of a solid educational
background in mathematics and computer science, research and
supervision experience, and lots of practical software engineering
experience allows him to tackle most development problems as a team
player or independently if need be.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Åsmund Ødegård</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/asmund/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/asmund/</guid><description>Founder and CEO of Expert Analytics. Enjoys developing small and large
systems in a number of languages and environments. Makes sure that
everyting is working well, both with clients and internally.</description></item></channel></rss>