<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Services on Expert Analytics</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/services/</link><description>Recent content in Services on Expert Analytics</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://expertanalytics.no/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Science and Machine Learning</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/services/datascience/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/services/datascience/</guid><description>&lt;p>Data Science is the science (and art) of extracting knowledge or insight from
raw data, whether that is applied to research or to industry. Extracting
meaning from and interpreting data requires tools and methods of multiple
disciplines such as mathematics, statistics, physics and computer science.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Advanced Data Visualization</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/services/visualization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/services/visualization/</guid><description>&lt;p>Concise and informative visualisation is the key for comprehension and
communication of data and analysis results. Especially these days where the
amount of data is often huge and traditional visualisation forms may not be
suitable. Treatments like data reduction or aggregation are then needed
to visualise the data efficiently.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>High Performance Computing</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/services/hpc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/services/hpc/</guid><description>&lt;p>In compute intensive applications, maximizing the performance of limited
hardware resources will always be a fundamental challenge. Be it numerical
solution of partial differential equations or Monte Carlo integration to
compute the multidimensional definite integral of some interesting function.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Systems Development</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/services/systems/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/services/systems/</guid><description>&lt;p>In today&amp;rsquo;s world of everything distributed, making a system do
the right thing is not always an easy task. In addition, requirements constantly evolve and business owners often like to use the newest and shiniest advancements. Developing software systems in a maintainable manner with focus on correctness becomes then a challenge. And we are up for that challenge - our software engineers usually consider the case more interesting, the more complex it gets.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>