<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About Us on Expert Analytics</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/</link><description>Recent content in About Us on Expert Analytics</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 20:02:32 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://expertanalytics.no/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Johannes Weissmann</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/johannes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 06:52:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/johannes/</guid><description>Johannes holds a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in computational physics from the Technical University uf Munich (TUM). He is a pragmatic problem solver capable of seeing the bigger picture and able to rapidly integrate into existing teams and projects.
He has worked with large scale data processing pipelines for the subsea and satellite industry. Currently, he is working with backends for in the financial sector. His preferred challenges are related to data structures and algorithms.</description></item><item><title>Vinzenz Gregor Eck</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/vinzenz/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 21:41:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/vinzenz/</guid><description>Vinzenz is a curious, pragmatic, creative problem solver. He holds a PhD in biomechanical engineering, focusing on stochastic simulations of the blood flow in the human arterial system. This interdisciplinary work included working within engineering, medicine, biology, software development and statistics.
His educational background is in mechanical engineering, with focus on numerical methods and bio-materials. Beside his studies, he has worked in several different fields such as virtual commissioning, petroleum research, biomechanics research.</description></item><item><title>Eivind Storm Aarnæs</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/eivind/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 11:05:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/eivind/</guid><description>Eivind has a masters degree in Computational Science from the University of Oslo, completed in 2016. His project investigated a particle system modeling linear elasticity, and accelerating linear algebra computations using GPUs. From the studies leading to his degree he has gained broad knowledge about algorithms, numerical mathematics, and programming in several languages.
Prior work experience includes teaching programming: mostly one-to-one teaching in a lab setting, but also as lecturing and live coding in plenary settings.</description></item><item><title>Jakob Schreiner</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/jakob/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 21:40:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/jakob/</guid><description>Jakob submitted his master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computational Science and Engineering at the University of Oslo in 2016. His educational background is in mathematics and computational science applied on mechanical problems using numerical methods. This has fuelled his interest for science and technology. He has mainly used Python and has substantial experience using numerical libraries such as Numpy/Scipy and FEniCS. He is also familiar with C/C++ and Java. His experience includes teaching introductory Python at the University of Oslo, mostly in one-to-one settings.</description></item><item><title>Guttorm Kvaal</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/guttorm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 21:40:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/guttorm/</guid><description>Guttorm is a curious person with an interest and enthusiasm for technology and problem solving. His academic background is focused around applied mathematics, programming, and physics. He submitted his master’s thesis the summer 2017 in the field of Computational Science and Engineering at the University of Oslo / Simula. In his work he performed numerical simulations of micro-particles inhaled into the human respiratory system. This involved writing Python scripts as well as modifying and working with open-source libraries, in addition to data analysis and supercomputer simulations.</description></item><item><title>Martin Alnæs</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/martin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 11:42:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/martin/</guid><description>Martin is an expert scientific programmer with a PhD in computational science and more than a decade of software engineering experience from research and industry. This combination of a solid educational background in mathematics and computer science, research and supervision experience, and lots of practical software engineering experience allows him to tackle most development problems as a team player or independently if need be.
He has worked on a wide range of software types including: web tools for scientific visualization using WebGL and JavaScript; embedded audio DSP programming in C; music sequencer software in C++; tools for diff and merge of Jupyter notebooks in Python; utilities for build and test systems in Python; high performance numerical computations in C++ and Fortran; mixed language API design for C++/Python libraries; automated C++ code generation tools with just in time compilation from Python; a declarative domain specific language and symbolic mathematics library for partial differential equations in Python; and software for solving partial differential equations and flow problems.</description></item><item><title>Andreas Slyngstad</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/andreas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 22:23:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/andreas/</guid><description>Andreas submitted his master’s thesis in applied mathematics from the University of Oslo and Simula Research Laboratory. In his thesis he investigated numerical schemes, for solving equations describing Fluid-Structure Interaction, using Python and FEniCS. His academic background has given him several tools and approaches for solving complex problems in a computational/software domain.
During his stay at Expert Analytics, he has been polishing his Python skills, while diving into C++ and Arduino technologies in his spare time.</description></item><item><title>Sebastian Gjertsen</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/sebastian/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 21:41:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/sebastian/</guid><description>Sebastian holds a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in applied mathematics from the University of Oslo and Simula Research Laboratory, finished in 2017. In his thesis he built a Fluid-Structure Interaction solver with Python using the FEniCS platform. This also included working with supercomputers parallelizing the computational efforts. During his studies he gained knowledge in algorithms, numerical computing and programming in different languages.
After graduating he worked for Shortcut AS, an app-development company, developing iOS apps and working with Splunk for monitoring and analyzing machine-generated big data.</description></item><item><title>Pia Zacharias</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/pia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 21:41:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/pia/</guid><description>Pia is a physicist with more than ten years of experience in scientific computing. She holds a PhD in astrophysics, which she obtained from the University of Freiburg, Germany in 2010. Her areas of expertise include numerical simulations of complex systems, statistical data analysis, signal processing, as well as the development of various feature recognition algorithms and visualization tools for large datasets.
Her analytical mindset and a solid background in physics provide her with a good foundation for finding solutions to complex problems.</description></item><item><title>Bernardo de Oliveira</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/bernardo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 11:04:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/bernardo/</guid><description>Bernardo obtained a PhD in Natural Sciences from the University of Oslo in 2014. He has over a decade of experience working with mathematical modelling and scientific computing in multiple fields including engineering, medicine, pharmacology and biology. His areas of expertise include numerical methods, simulation of multiphysics problems, signal processing and parallel computing. In recent years he has worked mostly with Python, but he also has experience with C++ and other programming languages.</description></item><item><title>Stian Lågstad</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/stian/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/stian/</guid><description>Stian finished his master&amp;rsquo;s thesis at The University of Oslo in the spring of 2016. During his time as a student, he got exposed to several programming languages, such as R, Python, Scheme, Java, and Javascript. In his work experience following that, first as a consultant for Knowit and then as a software engineer for Cognite, he spent a lot of time in the JVM world with Java and Scala.</description></item><item><title>Simen Tennøe</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/simen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/simen/</guid><description>Simen is a computational scientist who finished his Ph.D. in computational neuroscience in 2019. He has a background from computational astrophysics where he wrote software for finding clusters of galaxies in cosmological N-body simulations. His Ph.D. focused on quantifying uncertainties in computational models of neurons and neural networks and he created a Python toolbox for performing these calculations. Additionally, the work included creating a new specification for data storage, data analysis, and developing an educational neural network simulator.</description></item><item><title>Kent-Andre Mardal</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/kent/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/kent/</guid><description>Kent-Andre is a Professor of Applied Mathematics at the University of Oslo. He has extensive experience with computational modeling, multi-physics simulations, high-performance computing, and scientific software development (Python and C++).
Kent-Andre is experienced in multidisciplinary collaborations where advanced computational techniques are developed to solve real-life problems, in particular in the medicine. In XAL, he brings a broad experience in inter-disciplinary work as well as technical experience in scientific computing involving big data.</description></item><item><title>Trygve Bærland</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/trygve/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/trygve/</guid><description>Trygve holds a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Industrial Mathematics at NTNU in 2015, and has submitted a Ph.D. in Computational Mathematics at the University of Oslo in 2019. In his thesis Trygve developed, analysed and implemented efficient algorithms for solving systems of equations related to fluid flow in the brain. As such, he has substantial experience in development of numerical computer code &amp;ndash; mainly in Python, C and C++, and related libraries and tools for multi-language programming.</description></item><item><title>Anis Ayati</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/anis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/anis/</guid><description>Anis holds a PhD in Fluid Mechanics from the University of Oslo. Before joining us, he completed a three-year postdoctoral fellowship, which included research stays at PUC-Rio, Brazil and Princeton University, USA.
Anis&amp;rsquo;s main research interests are related to non-linear dynamics associated with multiphase phase flows, wind-generated waves, wall-bounded turbulence and aerodynamics. His research approach has mainly consisted of employing advanced experimental techniques including non-intrusive optical methods. He also has experience with numerical modeling and simulation.</description></item><item><title>Eigil Skjæveland</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/eigil/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/eigil/</guid><description>Eigil submitted his master&amp;rsquo;s thesis in computer science in 2017 after completing a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in applied mathematics. In his thesis he studied the application of databases to identify higher-level semantics in event data. During his studies, he also taught Python to freshman science students and worked on a project building a real estate statistics portal for an economic analysis NGO.
Before joining us, Eigil worked at Bekk Consulting where he gained experience with enterprise Java and Kotlin development in a large governmental department.</description></item><item><title>Alocias Mariadason</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/alocias/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/alocias/</guid><description>Alocias has a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in physics from the University of Oslo, submitted in spring 2018. The subject of the thesis was Quantum Monte Carlo Simulations of Quantum dots constrained in single- and double well potentials. He solved the numerical problem for both systems with new analytic expressions which had not been explicitly done before and a newer method with roots in machine learning to further improve upon the results. Solving these complex systems gave him a varied skill set within the fields of numerical methods, statistical analysis, mathematical optimization, symbolic computation and high performance computing.</description></item><item><title>Roar Emaus</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/roar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/roar/</guid><description>Roar has a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in High Energy Physics from the University of Oslo, completed in 2018. In his thesis he studied two different models of particle production at high energies, one statistical using the thermodynamical equations and one using the properties of a theoretical particle called Pomeron. He also has a practical background working as an electrician. All through his studies he worked with C, C++ and Python, but is adaptable to new systems and languages.</description></item><item><title>Alexander Fleischer</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/alexander/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/alexander/</guid><description>Alexander submitted his master&amp;rsquo;s thesis in Computational Physics at the University of Oslo in 2018. The subject of his thesis was Monte Carlo simulations of quantum dots constrained to different potential wells. For his thesis he developed software in C++ and Python, but he has experience with C and Java as well. His education has given him experience in solving complex physical and mathematical problems using various numerical methods and libraries.</description></item><item><title>Jonathan Feinberg</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/jonathan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/jonathan/</guid><description>Jonathan is a seasoned consultant with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry, with broad experience ranging from designing, building, testing and maintaining large scale programming projects.
He is a specialist within machine learning, stochastic modelling, statistics, and numerical programming. He has an eye for seeing possible solutions to the &amp;ldquo;hard&amp;rdquo; problems, and being able to quickly convert those into functioning prototypes.
He has a strong academical background with Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.</description></item><item><title>Ola Skavhaug</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ola/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ola/</guid><description>Ola is an experienced software developer, researcher, and project leader with a PhD in scientific programming. His main areas of technical expertise are mathematical and numerical software development, algorithm development, advanced scripting with modern scripting languages, parallel programming, software testing and deployment, library design, systems programming and scientific visualization.
Through his work, he has obtained an extensive set of skills that allows him to understand and solve challenges in collaboration with customers.</description></item><item><title>Åsmund Ødegård</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/asmund/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/asmund/</guid><description>Åsmund is a senior software developer, project leader, and researcher, with more than 20 years of professional experience. After spending 13 years at Simula Research Laboratory, Norway’s top-ranked ICT research institution, he founded Expert Analytics in 2013, together with Ola Skavhaug.
Through various positions in his career, he has obtained a broad set of technical and management skills, which he now put to good use as both Managing Director and a Senior Consultant in Expert Analytics.</description></item></channel></rss>