<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>C&#43;&#43; on Expert Analytics</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cpp/</link><description>Recent content in C&#43;&#43; on Expert Analytics</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 13:49:36 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://expertanalytics.no/training/cpp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to C&#43;&#43;</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cpp/introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 13:38:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cpp/introduction/</guid><description>An introduction to the C++ programming language. An excellent starting point for those who are familiar with programming, but who have never worked with C++.
Course Content The course will cover the following topics:
C++ specific syntax Data types and typecasting Overloading of functions and operators I/O in C++ Pointers Commonly used standard library classes Prerequisite Some experience with other programming languages.
Duration: 2-6 hours Tools Introduced C++ C++ is a widely used general-purpose, strongly typed, compiled programming language.</description></item><item><title>Numerical C&#43;&#43;</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cpp/numerical/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:06:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cpp/numerical/</guid><description>If a program is performing any form of numerical operations, it is likely that it will become the program bottleneck. To minimize the impact of the bottleneck, care must be taken to ensure that the code being executed is as optimized as possible.
Course Content In this course we will introduce the numerical library Armadillo. We sill give an overview of the syntax, and how to employ the language to solve large scale numerical problems.</description></item><item><title>Templating and Metaprogramming</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cpp/templating/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:14:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cpp/templating/</guid><description>Templates are a powerful tool in C++ that allows you to write generalized functions and classes, enabling them to depend on free parameters that are set whenever they are used. This is commonly used to create functions that can take arguments of any type as input.
With the C++11 standard, variadic templates were introduced. Variadic templates not only allows you to make typesafe variadic functions, but also enables templates to be used for metaprogramming: writing code that writes code.</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cpp/machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 14:15:05 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/training/cpp/machine-learning/</guid><description>Machine learning is the field of study that gives computers the ability to learn without being explicitly programmed. It is the study and construction of algorithms that can learn from and make predictions on data. Such algorithms operate by building a model from example inputs in order to make data-driven predictions or decisions, rather than following strictly static program instructions. The term &amp;ldquo;machine learning&amp;rdquo; is an umbrella term and can be used to describe one of the following topics:</description></item></channel></rss>