<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>High Performance Computing on Expert Analytics</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/services/hpc/</link><description>Recent content in High Performance Computing on Expert Analytics</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://expertanalytics.no/services/hpc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Felix Kohler</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/felix/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/felix/</guid><description>&lt;p>Felix is a research scientist with experience in data analysis and scientific programming. He holds a PhD in physics and worked in various interdisciplinary projects both as a Postdoc and Researcher in an academic setting as well as a senior researcher in industry. Felix has a background in both experimental studies as well as mathematical and numerical modelling. His creativity, analytical mindset and scientific experience provide him with a solid foundation for finding solutions to complex problems.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Marco Nava</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/marco/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/marco/</guid><description>&lt;p>Marco holds a Ph.D in computational Condensed Matter Physics, with
a strong focus on quantum and classical atomistic simulation methods.
Throughout his decade-long career he has worked on both software development -
mainly in C++ and Python - and research intensive projects across several
research fields ranging from low-temperature physics to computational chemistry
and biophysics. This experience, along with his robust mathematical and
coding background, allows him to be a broad and thorough problem solver, well
capable of working both independently and as a team member.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Naeeme Danesh Moghaddam</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/naeeme/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/naeeme/</guid><description>&lt;p>Naeeme is an enthusiastic software developer with many years of experience as a
project engineer. Before joining our team, she worked in the field of 3D
modelling and CFD simulation of reactive and non-reactive flows, employing
high-performance computing and immersive virtual reality environments to
optimize the performance of industrial units. This allowed her to gain
experience in solving complex problems using her expertise in software
development combined with her knowledge in fluid dynamics, chemical
thermodynamics, mass and heat transfer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Robert Solli</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/robert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/robert/</guid><description>&lt;p>Robert Solli is a specialist in scientific programming, with expertise in
mathematical optimisation, statistical analysis and machine learning. He has
solved a varied set of problems with this skillset, from understanding complex
physical systems to increasing student volunteer participation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Robert Hagala</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/rh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/rh/</guid><description>&lt;p>Robert has a PhD in astrophysics, with a specialisation in
cosmological simulations. He is experienced with numerical
modelling of physical systems, statistical analysis of large data sets,
high-performance computing, and cloud based applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ata Karakci</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ata/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ata/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ata holds a PhD in physics with specialisation in astrophysics which he obtained from Brown University in 2014. Before joining the Expert Analytics team, he has worked as a postdoctoral researcher at the University of Oslo and Universite Paris VII. His expertise includes statistical analysis of large data sets, numerical modelling, signal processing, imaging, and programming.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diako Darian</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/diako/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/diako/</guid><description>&lt;p>Diako holds a Ph.D. in Computational Mathematics from the University of Oslo. As
a student at both Mathematics and Physics departments at the University of Oslo,
he has acquired a broad knowledge in various physical and mathematical theories,
and numerical methods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Roar Emaus</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/roar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/roar/</guid><description>&lt;p>Roar has a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in High Energy Physics from the University of Oslo,
completed in 2018. In his thesis he studied two different models of particle
production at high energies, one statistical using the thermodynamical
equations and one using the properties of a theoretical particle called
Pomeron.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alexander Fleischer</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/alexander/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/alexander/</guid><description>&lt;p>Alexander is a senior software developer specializing in backend and system
development in Python.
His experience with Python dates back to 2010, and he has been working
professionally with system development in Python since 2018.
During his career, he has worked in several platform and product teams
in both the public transport sector and the energy sector.
Alexander holds a master&amp;rsquo;s thesis in computational quantum physics from
the University of Oslo.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Andreas Slyngstad</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/andreas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/andreas/</guid><description>&lt;p>Andreas submitted his master’s thesis in applied mathematics from the
University of Oslo and Simula Research Laboratory. In his thesis he
investigated numerical schemes, for solving equations describing
Fluid-Structure Interaction, using Python and FEniCS. His academic background
has given him several tools and approaches for solving complex problems in a
computational/software domain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Eivind Storm Aarnæs</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/eivind/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/eivind/</guid><description>&lt;p>Eivind has a masters degree in Computational Science from the
University of Oslo, completed in 2016. His project investigated a
particle system modeling linear elasticity, and accelerating linear
algebra computations using GPUs. From the studies leading to his
degree he has gained broad knowledge about algorithms, numerical
mathematics, and programming in several languages.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vinzenz Gregor Eck</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/vinzenz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/vinzenz/</guid><description>&lt;p>Vinzenz is a curious, pragmatic, creative problem solver. He holds a
PhD in biomechanical engineering, focusing on stochastic simulations
of the blood flow in the human arterial system. This interdisciplinary
work included working within engineering, medicine, biology, software
development and statistics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ola Skavhaug</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ola/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ola/</guid><description>Founder and CEO of Expert Analytics. Loves mixing high and low-level languages to combine flexibility with performance.</description></item><item><title>Åsmund Ødegård</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/asmund/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/asmund/</guid><description>Founder and Board chair of Expert Analytics. Enjoys developing small and large
systems in a number of languages and environments. Makes sure that
everyting is working well, both with clients and internally.</description></item></channel></rss>