<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Shyft on Expert Analytics</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/projects/shyft/</link><description>Recent content in Shyft on Expert Analytics</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://expertanalytics.no/projects/shyft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Roar Emaus</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/roar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/roar/</guid><description>&lt;p>Roar has a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in High Energy Physics from the University of Oslo,
completed in 2018. In his thesis he studied two different models of particle
production at high energies, one statistical using the thermodynamical
equations and one using the properties of a theoretical particle called
Pomeron.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Andreas Slyngstad</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/andreas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/andreas/</guid><description>&lt;p>Andreas submitted his master’s thesis in applied mathematics from the
University of Oslo and Simula Research Laboratory. In his thesis he
investigated numerical schemes, for solving equations describing
Fluid-Structure Interaction, using Python and FEniCS. His academic background
has given him several tools and approaches for solving complex problems in a
computational/software domain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Eivind Storm Aarnæs</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/eivind/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/eivind/</guid><description>&lt;p>Eivind has a masters degree in Computational Science from the
University of Oslo, completed in 2016. His project investigated a
particle system modeling linear elasticity, and accelerating linear
algebra computations using GPUs. From the studies leading to his
degree he has gained broad knowledge about algorithms, numerical
mathematics, and programming in several languages.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vinzenz Gregor Eck</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/vinzenz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/vinzenz/</guid><description>&lt;p>Vinzenz is a curious, pragmatic, creative problem solver. He holds a
PhD in biomechanical engineering, focusing on stochastic simulations
of the blood flow in the human arterial system. This interdisciplinary
work included working within engineering, medicine, biology, software
development and statistics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ola Skavhaug</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ola/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ola/</guid><description>Founder and CEO of Expert Analytics. Loves mixing high and low-level languages to combine flexibility with performance.</description></item></channel></rss>