<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Advanced Data Visualization on Expert Analytics</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/services/visualization/</link><description>Recent content in Advanced Data Visualization on Expert Analytics</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://expertanalytics.no/services/visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Daniel Marelius Bjørnstad</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/daniel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/daniel/</guid><description>&lt;p>Daniel is a seasoned software developer with a PhD in neuroscience, specializing in data analysis and cloud software
development. With expertise in multiple stages of project development, Daniel’s work spans from the initial definition
of project goals and value propositions to the deployment of final products, including services, dashboards, reports,
production models, and APIs. His background in neuroscience provides a strong foundation in complex data processing and
analysis, allowing him to tackle challenging problems in diverse domains. He started working professionally with software development in 2016.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kine Onsum Moseid</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/kine/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/kine/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kine is an organized scientific programmer that likes to solve problems from a big picture approach. She submitted her PhD thesis in Climate Science in December of 2021, and during her doctorate she analyzed radiation and air pollution data from a multitude of climate model simulations and compared them with observations. This work gave insight in big data analytics and visualisation, especially regarding time series and how to avoid common pitfalls like comparing apples and oranges. She enjoys working with large datasets, learning new things, and communicating/teaching science.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sebastian Franco Ulloa</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/sebas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/sebas/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sebastian is a curious person always looking to learn about
new topics and combining them into novel solutions to complex
problems. He received his PhD in biocomputional sciences in
March 2021 from the Italian Institute of Technology/University
of Bologna, where he studied how nanomaterials interact with
physiological environments. He is experienced in molecular
simulations, data visualization, and scientific writing.
In more recent years, Sebastian has been applying bioinformatic
methods to genomics, proteomics, and transcriptomics data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Robert Solli</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/robert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/robert/</guid><description>&lt;p>Robert Solli is a specialist in scientific programming, with expertise in
mathematical optimisation, statistical analysis and machine learning. He has
solved a varied set of problems with this skillset, from understanding complex
physical systems to increasing student volunteer participation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diako Darian</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/diako/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/diako/</guid><description>&lt;p>Diako holds a Ph.D. in Computational Mathematics from the University of Oslo. As
a student at both Mathematics and Physics departments at the University of Oslo,
he has acquired a broad knowledge in various physical and mathematical theories,
and numerical methods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guttorm Kvaal</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/guttorm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/guttorm/</guid><description>&lt;p>Guttorm is a curious person with an interest and enthusiasm for
technology and problem solving. His academic background is focused
around applied mathematics, programming, and physics. He submitted his
master’s thesis the summer 2017 in the field of Computational Science
and Engineering at the University of Oslo / Simula.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ola Skavhaug</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ola/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ola/</guid><description>Founder and CEO of Expert Analytics. Loves mixing high and low-level languages to combine flexibility with performance.</description></item></channel></rss>