<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Advanced Data Visualization on Expert Analytics</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/services/visualization/</link><description>Recent content in Advanced Data Visualization on Expert Analytics</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://expertanalytics.no/services/visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kine Onsum Moseid</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/kine/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/kine/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kine is an organized scientific programmer that likes to solve problems from a big picture approach. She submitted her PhD thesis in Climate Science in December of 2021, and during her doctorate she analyzed radiation and air pollution data from a multitude of climate model simulations and compared them with observations. This work gave insight in big data analytics and visualisation, especially regarding time series and how to avoid common pitfalls like comparing apples and oranges. She enjoys working with large datasets, learning new things, and communicating/teaching science.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Naeeme Danesh Moghaddam</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/naeeme/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/naeeme/</guid><description>&lt;p>Naeeme is an enthusiastic software developer with many years of experience as a
project engineer. Before joining our team, she worked in the field of 3D
modelling and CFD simulation of reactive and non-reactive flows, employing
high-performance computing and immersive virtual reality environments to
optimize the performance of industrial units. This allowed her to gain
experience in solving complex problems using her expertise in software
development combined with her knowledge in fluid dynamics, chemical
thermodynamics, mass and heat transfer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sebastian Franco Ulloa</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/sebas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/sebas/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sebastian is a curious person always looking to learn about
new topics and combining them into novel solutions to complex
problems. He received his PhD in biocomputional sciences in
March 2021 from the Italian Institute of Technology/University
of Bologna, where he studied how nanomaterials interact with
physiological environments. He is experienced in molecular
simulations, data visualization, and scientific writing.
In more recent years, Sebastian has been applying bioinformatic
methods to genomics, proteomics, and transcriptomics data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Robert Solli</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/robert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/robert/</guid><description>&lt;p>Robert Solli is a specialist in scientific programming, with expertise in
mathematical optimisation, statistical analysis and machine learning. He has
solved a varied set of problems with this skillset, from understanding complex
physical systems to increasing student volunteer participation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Robert Hagala</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/rh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/rh/</guid><description>&lt;p>Robert has a PhD in astrophysics, with a specialisation in
cosmological simulations. He is experienced with numerical
modelling of physical systems, statistical analysis of large data sets,
high-performance computing, and cloud based applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diako Darian</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/diako/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/diako/</guid><description>&lt;p>Diako holds a Ph.D. in Computational Mathematics from the University of Oslo. As
a student at both Mathematics and Physics departments at the University of Oslo,
he has acquired a broad knowledge in various physical and mathematical theories,
and numerical methods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guttorm Kvaal</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/guttorm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/guttorm/</guid><description>&lt;p>Guttorm is a curious person with an interest and enthusiasm for
technology and problem solving. His academic background is focused
around applied mathematics, programming, and physics. He submitted his
master’s thesis the summer 2017 in the field of Computational Science
and Engineering at the University of Oslo / Simula.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vinzenz Gregor Eck</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/vinzenz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/vinzenz/</guid><description>&lt;p>Vinzenz is a curious, pragmatic, creative problem solver. He holds a
PhD in biomechanical engineering, focusing on stochastic simulations
of the blood flow in the human arterial system. This interdisciplinary
work included working within engineering, medicine, biology, software
development and statistics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ola Skavhaug</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ola/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ola/</guid><description>Founder and CSO of Expert Analytics. Loves mixing high and low level languages
to join flexibility and high perfomance computing.</description></item></channel></rss>