<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data Science and Machine Learning on Expert Analytics</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/services/datascience/</link><description>Recent content in Data Science and Machine Learning on Expert Analytics</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://expertanalytics.no/services/datascience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Therese Renstrøm</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/therese/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/therese/</guid><description>&lt;p>Therese holds a Ph.D. in Experimental Nuclear Physics from the University of Oslo. Her thesis was awarded the YARA Birkeland Prize for outstanding contributions to
innovation and industry. Her main fields of expertise are developing real-time analytics tools and implementing machine learning and statistical models. The past years,
she has developed prototypes and set into production software tools for the petroleum-, processing- and medical industry.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kine Onsum Moseid</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/kine/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/kine/</guid><description>&lt;p>Kine is an organized scientific programmer that likes to solve problems from a big picture approach. She submitted her PhD thesis in Climate Science in December of 2021, and during her doctorate she analyzed radiation and air pollution data from a multitude of climate model simulations and compared them with observations. This work gave insight in big data analytics and visualisation, especially regarding time series and how to avoid common pitfalls like comparing apples and oranges. She enjoys working with large datasets, learning new things, and communicating/teaching science.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Solveig Næss</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/solveig/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/solveig/</guid><description>Solveig is an enthusiastic problem solver with strong collaboration skills. With a PhD in brain physics, she enjoys applying mathematics, physics and programming to develop new methods and answer complex questions.</description></item><item><title>Sebastian Franco Ulloa</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/sebas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/sebas/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sebastian is a curious person always looking to learn about
new topics and combining them in any way he can think of.
He received his PhD in biocomputional sciences in March 2021
from the University of Bologna/Italian Institute of Technology.
Sebastian&amp;rsquo;s reasearch has been focused on how nanomaterials
interact with physiological environments. He is experienced
in molecular simulations, data visualization,
and scientific writing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Robert Solli</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/robert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/robert/</guid><description>&lt;p>Robert Solli is a specialist in scientific programming, with expertise in
mathematical optimisation, statistical analysis and machine learning. He has
solved a varied set of problems with this skillset, from understanding complex
physical systems to increasing student volunteer participation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Robert Hagala</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/rh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/rh/</guid><description>&lt;p>Robert has a PhD in astrophysics, with a specialisation in
cosmological simulations. He is experienced with numerical
modelling of physical systems, statistical analysis of large data sets,
high-performance computing, and cloud based applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ada Ortiz-Carbonell</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ada/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ada/</guid><description>Ada is a senior researcher with 20 years of academic experience in the field of Astrophysics during which she taught, mentored students, organized several international conferences and led her own research projects. She is engaged in scientific communication and outreach, having published two books, delivered public lectures, appeared in the media explaining solar physics to a general audience and been nominated as TED speaker. She decided to take on a new challenge and apply her skills in the industry. Ada enjoys analyzing complex problems as well as extracting valuable information out of data.</description></item><item><title>Ata Karakci</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ata/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ata/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ata holds a PhD in physics with specialisation in astrophysics which he obtained from Brown University in 2014. Before joining the Expert Analytics team, he has worked as a postdoctoral researcher at the University of Oslo and Universite Paris VII. His expertise includes statistical analysis of large data sets, numerical modelling, signal processing, imaging, and programming.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Anis Ayati</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/anis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/anis/</guid><description>&lt;p>Anis holds a PhD in Fluid Mechanics from the University of Oslo. Before joining us, he completed a three-year postdoctoral fellowship, which included research stays at PUC-Rio, Brazil and Princeton University, USA.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pia Zacharias</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/pia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/pia/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pia is a physicist with more than ten years of experience in scientific
programming and data analysis. She holds a PhD in physics, which she obtained
from the University of Freiburg, Germany in 2010. She has been working as a
researcher, mentor and lecturer in astrophysics at different research
institutions across Europe before she joined Expert Analytics in 2018.
Her areas of expertise include numerical simulations of complex physical systems,
statistical data analysis and signal processing, as well machine learning applications
and visualization and handling of large datasets.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jonathan Feinberg</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/jonathan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/jonathan/</guid><description>&lt;p>Jonathan is a specialist within machine learning, stochastic modelling,
statistics, and numerical programming. He has an eye for seeing possible
solutions to the &amp;ldquo;hard&amp;rdquo; problems, and being able to quickly convert those into
functioning prototypes.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>