<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The ADAM platform on Expert Analytics</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/projects/adam/</link><description>Recent content in The ADAM platform on Expert Analytics</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://expertanalytics.no/projects/adam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gry M. Tveten</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/gry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/gry/</guid><description>&lt;p>Gry is a curious, efficient and pragmatic problem solver. She completed her PhD in experimental nuclear physics at the University of Oslo in 2013 and most of her PhD work was carried out at CERN. She has 6 years of post doc experience. Her recent work focused on understanding how the elements are created in stellar processes. This research required developing detection systems, analyzing data, visualization and carrying out complex simulations. She has also teaching experience, including course development at university level and has led her own projects since she completed her PhD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diako Darian</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/diako/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/diako/</guid><description>&lt;p>Diako holds a Ph.D. in Computational Mathematics from the University of Oslo. As
a student at both Mathematics and Physics departments at the University of Oslo,
he has acquired a broad knowledge in various physical and mathematical theories,
and numerical methods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Roar Emaus</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/roar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/roar/</guid><description>&lt;p>Roar has a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in High Energy Physics from the University of Oslo,
completed in 2018. In his thesis he studied two different models of particle
production at high energies, one statistical using the thermodynamical
equations and one using the properties of a theoretical particle called
Pomeron.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Andreas Slyngstad</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/andreas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/andreas/</guid><description>&lt;p>Andreas submitted his master’s thesis in applied mathematics from the
University of Oslo and Simula Research Laboratory. In his thesis he
investigated numerical schemes, for solving equations describing
Fluid-Structure Interaction, using Python and FEniCS. His academic background
has given him several tools and approaches for solving complex problems in a
computational/software domain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vinzenz Gregor Eck</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/vinzenz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/vinzenz/</guid><description>&lt;p>Vinzenz is a curious, pragmatic, creative problem solver. He holds a
PhD in biomechanical engineering, focusing on stochastic simulations
of the blood flow in the human arterial system. This interdisciplinary
work included working within engineering, medicine, biology, software
development and statistics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ola Skavhaug</title><link>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ola/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://expertanalytics.no/about/employees/ola/</guid><description>Founder and CSO of Expert Analytics. Loves mixing high and low level languages
to join flexibility and high perfomance computing.</description></item></channel></rss>